UMESH KUMAR SINGH

Alstonia Estate, PI 1&2, Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh, 201310 +91-9708306322 | Umeshkes91@gmail.com

Profile Summary:

Having 1.2 Years of relevant experience as a full stack developer. Created and lead 15+ websites with .Net Framework, C#, MS SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Ajax, API integration etc. My strength are coding skills, amazing logic building, and problem solving technique, ability to work independently as well as in team.

Work Experience:

1. Webkul Software Pvt. Ltd.

Noida

Trainee Software Engineer Jan 2023 - June 2023

Work Area: WEB DEVELOPMENT

Technologies: C#, .NET Framework, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap.

Description: Developed addons and improved software modules.

2. CSAT Systems Pvt. Ltd.

Noida

Junior Software Developer Aug 2023 – Present

Work Area: WEB DEVELOPMENT

Technologies: C#, .NET Core, MS SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery, Ajax.

Description: Develop and Maintain softwares.

Technical Competencies:

C#, Java, PHP

- MySQL, MS SQL
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Paytm Integration, Email Integration, SMS Integration
- .Net Framework, ASP.Net
- DSA (Basic)

Latest Projects:

- **Web Order-** A Complete Solution for Bar and Restaurant with home delivery and take away options, integrated with Paytm payment facility.
- QR Scan- Scan QR Code to view and Order restaurants item on dining.
- Hand Held- A software to Order bars and restaurant Items on selected table for guest. Also admin can Print Bill,
 Split Bill, Cancel Bill and Settle bill option with tax and offers.
- Dashboard- A Software to manage daily, monthly and periodic purchase report for Small and large business,
 Hotel and restaurant.

Previous Projects:

- <u>CS-Cart Auction | Bidding Website on CS-Cart WebKul</u> I added many features like restart auction, show winning message to winner, automatic bid option etc.
- <u>CS-Cart Advanced RMA | Return merchandise Authorization Addon for CS-Cart WebKul</u> added new features like "guest user can able to order products" and fixed many majored bugs.
- <u>CS-Cart Geolocation Language and Currency Converter (webkul.com)</u> Changed Geolocation api and improved the functionality of addon.

Academic Background

B.Tech (CSE): Galgotias University, Greater Noida	7.54 CGPA	Aug 2019 – May 2023
Intermediate (PCM): HD Jain College, Ara	62.40 %	Mar 2016 – Mar 2018
High School (IT): M.D Carmel School, Jagdishpur	10 CGPA	Mar 2015 – Mar 2016

Cerifications: ⊚DSA using Java (NPTEL) ⊚AI-ML (AICTE) ⊚Cyber Security (AICTE) ⊚Cloud & Network Security (AICTE)